Theme Tune: [music playing]
Kevin: Hello farmers and welcome to another episode of the harvest season. My name is Kevin
Chelsea: And my name is Chelsea.
Kevin: and neither of us are named Cody, unfortunately.
Chelsea: Neither of us are Cody.
Kevin: And we are here today to talk about the curse of Neopets.
Chelsea: WOOOOO!
Chelsea: This is some deep lore we're getting into.
Kevin: Yeah, so yeah, so once again.
Chelsea: This is attempt number five to record this.
Kevin: I guess it's been two weeks now that I don't remember.
Kevin: Regardless, last time I was on, you and Cody were on and trying to do a Neopets episode
Kevin: and then things went bad. So I hopped on. Well, actually, no back up.
Kevin: Chelsea and I were going to finish it, but then things happened.
Kevin: And so I had to finish it solo. And then this week,
Kevin: Cody and Chelsea were going to record and do it proper, but things happened.
Kevin: And so here we are again with...
Kevin: Kevin instead of Cody again, hello everyone!
Chelsea: We are here! We made it!
Kevin: We made it. So yeah, we're gonna talk about Neopets because we like Neopets I guess,
Kevin: and there's Cottagecore in there somewhere. It's the early days of Cottagecore, one could argue.
Kevin: But before that, as usual, we have lots of our usual Cottagecore game news. So we'll cover
Kevin: some updates and stuff like that. But before that, Chelsea, what's
Chelsea: I have been riddled with a kidney stone, so that's kind of taken over my whole life.
Kevin: That's not great.
Chelsea: I went to the emergency room, totally fun, and I have the good meds right now, so that's
Kevin: Yeah, I am very thankful for that.
Chelsea: why I'm able to record right now.
Kevin: Um, yeah, my condolences.
Kevin: I've never had a kidney stone.
Kevin: They terrify me to be very frank.
Kevin: Um, I've only heard the horror stories and, Oh, just crossing my fingers,
Kevin: knocking on the wood and everything.
Chelsea: I hope I don't even have the kind that can be cured with lifestyle changes because my I have like a
Chelsea: Deformity in my kidney from when I was born. So my body just is super good at making stones
Kevin: Oh no.
Kevin: Oh no, all that stuff.
Chelsea: And it's like a one in hundred thousand
Chelsea: People have this condition. So I'm like, I'm just one of the lucky ones. I think I've met one person who's ever had it
Chelsea: so
Kevin: um my condolences um hope you get through that soon um honestly not much better on my hand
Chelsea: Yeah, no
Chelsea: Thanks, how about you Kevin? Oh
Chelsea: My god
Kevin: because i've been working like a maniac um this is like the second week in a row i've had to work
Chelsea: Oh no!
Kevin: and because of that my body has been weakened and i've gotten sick again nothing major just
Kevin: You know, cold sniffle stuff, but it's...
Kevin: Oh, I'm tired.
Kevin: I've snuck in, you know, a minute of Pocopi here or there,
Kevin: but nothing to write home about, so...
Chelsea: Well luckily we have like 20 some years of Neopets to go off of.
Kevin: That's what...
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, we're good on that, for sure.
Kevin: Yeah, but that's what we've been up to, surviving!
Chelsea: Woo! Peak performance!
Kevin: 8th purple. Oh, honestly.
Kevin: This is the energy I like to bring to the podcast.
Kevin: So that's fine.
Kevin: So with that out of the way, let's let's start looking at
Kevin: some so they're looking at some news.
Kevin: Shall we first up all lofty of the multiplayer focus the
Kevin: standard cottage core sandboxing crafting type game.
Kevin: It's a lot of the usual buzzwords, but it's multiplayer.
Kevin: It's you know, I
Kevin: guess it's MMO-y because there's a point in the trail they show a lot of
Kevin: characters at once. Anyways, the early access is dropping November 3rd which
Kevin: hey good for them they're announcing a date but it's only early access. I've
Kevin: well documented how much I'm not a fan of extended early access periods but I
Kevin: get it but you know so be it. I overall like I don't know I still have trouble
Kevin: with the game standing out to me.
Kevin: It looks competently made,
Kevin: I just don't see a lot that stands out.
Kevin: Like, I don't know what the multiplayer is going to add.
Kevin: If anything, when you look at other, you know, MMOs,
Kevin: they have raids or events that require lots of people.
Kevin: I'm just not fully seeing how
Kevin: that's going to be translated here.
Kevin: What are your thoughts, Chelsea?
Chelsea: Oh, I was gonna say, is there like a farmer's market, maybe?
Chelsea: Like, where all the characters come together?
Chelsea: I don't know how it's gonna be a big multiplayer game, but I like the idea.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, I don't fully know either I see there's looks like maybe
Kevin: You do big builds together, which could be one way, but I don't know
Kevin: Again, if that's gonna be fully sustainable, but I guess we'll see on November 3rd because that's when our early access drops
Kevin: it's gonna be 30 USD with a
Kevin: 17% discount so it goes down to 25 USD at launch
Chelsea: 17%!
Kevin: And no
Kevin: As far as I know, no limit on what
Chelsea: Yeah, it doesn't show an end for the early access, so...
Chelsea: [clears throat]
Kevin: Uh, and that will be on PC and Mac. There you go, Cody. Uh, nothing on consoles yet. Yeah
Chelsea: Cool.
Chelsea: Yeah, Cody gets her shot now.
Kevin: I will say the animals are pretty cute the pets and stuff. Uh, I do like the art the art style is vibrant
Kevin: Good luck to them, nonetheless.
Kevin: Next up, to update to Outbound, the wildlife update.
Kevin: There are adding 34 animals in total.
Kevin: It is out now.
Kevin: And you can go around, use new camera feature
Kevin: that you can snap, you know, do your little Pokemon
Kevin: snap with these animals and fill up a journal.
Chelsea: I was gonna say "Pokémon Snap!"
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, basically.
Kevin: I love the last half so much.
Kevin: There's a new journal that basically serves as your little deck slash collection hub.
Kevin: There are binoculars located throughout the environment to zoom out to see other
Kevin: animals like a dolphin out in the ocean that might not be near your RV.
Kevin: And yeah, that is the bulk of this update.
Kevin: I think it's fine. I like animals. I like Pokemon Snap, so the overall idea is cool.
Kevin: I just think and you know
Kevin: Bound the game with the RV focus that they should really, you know, tie it all together, too
Chelsea: every update for the RB, it increased the stats of the RB.
Kevin: Or another level, give me my animal photography lab on top, I don't know, something like that.
Chelsea: [laughs]
Kevin: You can decorate your RV with photos, which is nice, but I just want to see the RV good.
Chelsea: Grow some wings and rocket ship
Kevin: If they weren't cowards, yes, we give it the rockets if they weren't.
Chelsea: Give us the rockets you cowards
Kevin: Exactly. Regardless, I overall, I like it.
Kevin: I feel like I said, I like animals and there's a healthy mix of animals.
Kevin: There's insects, there's obviously mammals, birds, sea creatures.
Kevin: So there you go. And now that's fun.
Kevin: All right, next up, another update to Disney Dreamlight Valley.
Kevin: And this time it's not my usual, oh this character wasn't already in this one's sensible in my opinion.
Kevin: We talked about I think before Oogie Boogie's Halloween event.
Kevin: We've gotten more details on it.
Kevin: They call it the Season of Scares. It is a six-week series of quests with Oogie Boogie and his nonsense.
Kevin: What I like about this update, even though it is, you know, live service and timed and whatnot and unlocks over six weeks.
Kevin: If you
Kevin: start before November 4th, that's the date they've laid it, you can do basically the
Kevin: quests at your own pace, and you can unlock everything, which is really nice. You do not
Kevin: have to figure it, fill it out in a limited area. But yeah, and it will, and if you do
Kevin: miss the cutoff date of November 4th, you can in fact play it again next year. It will
Kevin: return. So that's really exciting that they've laid that all out. I think that's a great
Kevin: way of doing these holiday timed events.
Kevin: You can unlock Zero, Jack Skellington's little ghost dog, which is amazing. I love Zero so
Kevin: much. He's adorable. Yes. It gets played on both holidays, so yes. Zero with or without
Chelsea: Is Nightmare Before Christmas a Halloween movie or a Christmas movie to you?
Chelsea: Yeah, exactly.
Chelsea: Yep.
Kevin: the antlers, basically. And Oogie Boogie himself will be unlockable at Deer Valley, I suppose,
Chelsea: Oh, exactly.
Kevin: which is very cool. I like Oogie Boogie. This is, okay, this is a very minor gripe,
Kevin: or not even a gripe, just a quirk, but a lot of Oogie Boogie art, including this one, paints
Kevin: him as green. I kind of like the more plain, just, you know, white burlap sec looking Oogie,
Kevin: but that's just me. Either way, I like Oogie a lot. He's delightful, but it's something.
Kevin: He's scary. Any other thoughts on that, Chelsea?
Chelsea: [laughs]
Chelsea: Yeah.
Chelsea: I'm just looking at the schedule, it looks pretty reasonable.
Kevin: Yeah. Yes. Yeah. Yeah. I think they do for the holidays and such, since it's kind of
Chelsea: I didn't realize that it was like a live game.
Chelsea: But I haven't played Dreamlight Value, but...
Chelsea: I didn't realize that they had like actual timed events.
Kevin: Animal Crossing-esque, you know, but yeah. Either way, like I said, I think it's a great
Kevin: way of doing it. It's not just a day, it's over a period of time, and you can, again,
Kevin: do it at your own pace if you start it before November 4th, or do it next year when it comes
Kevin: Whoa, good for you
Kevin: boogie-boogie in Greenlight Valley
Kevin: Okay, next up going from the scary to possibly even scarier
Kevin: petunias purgatory
Kevin: That is the rusty like the game
Kevin: On the bottom of your screen with it woods farming, but with a horror twist. They are doing the
Kevin: automation update
Kevin: Starting at level 13. You'll be able to automate both planting seeds and refilling your animal bait buildings. I
Kevin: kind of
Kevin: Shocked I guess because if it's a game that's gonna be overlaid my computer
Kevin: I assume the vast majority of it would already be automated
Kevin: as
Chelsea: Well yeah, isn't that the whole point?
Kevin: That's what I would think right this is my gripe with these games like I I'm not good at multitasking
Kevin: And so I want to focus on one or the other but if it's gonna be overlaid you
Kevin: Think that would be an idle sort of game
Kevin: I don't remember the details on all of Tunia's...
Kevin: Purgatory, so there I might not be giving enough credit, but it shocks me like planting seeds was not already automated
Chelsea: I am laughing at the bug fixes and improvements. At the bottom, it says "Keep farming and don't go insane."
Kevin: This is already out now and I love their dev team named Dead Possum Games, check it out
Chelsea: So that's setting the vibe for this game.
Kevin: if you're interested.
Chelsea: The Burr months are the best months.
Kevin: Okay lastly, my favorite update of this bunch because David Diver never stops delivering
Chelsea: Woo!
Kevin: and in ways you would never expect.
Chelsea: He's just on every side quest.
Kevin: So David Diver has crossed over with Godzilla, crossed over with the Like a Dragon series
Kevin: specifically Ichiban, and they have crossed over with Nikkei Goddess.
Kevin: So, the natural follow-up, in my opinion, the through-line is very clear here, Guilty Gear
Kevin: Strive! The Arksys fighting game series. Are you familiar with Guilty Gear at all, Chelsea?
Chelsea: *laughs* The obvious next level, come on!
Chelsea: Not overly, um, but I wanna ask when Dave the Diver is gonna be in Super Smash.
Kevin: No, okay. So, oh, if only. I mean, that's one of my comments because
Kevin: the content here, they're adding some Guilty Gear stuff into Dave the Diver.
Kevin: There's a rhythm in a game that's popped up in Dave the Diver, and so they're adding a couple
Kevin: of one level to that using the game, the song, excuse me, The Disaster of Passion,
Kevin: which is a great little J-pop. Guilty Gear has fantastic music. If you haven't heard it,
Kevin: I recommend listening to it. It's just a fun little J-pop sort of tune.
Kevin: The character "May" is going to be the focus.
Kevin: She's going to at least up some degree and provide a new weapon based on her anchor because
Kevin: in Guilty Gear she fights with a giant anchor.
Kevin: And so you can use her like an anchor gun underwater with Dave.
Kevin: There will be a few decorations including May's speaker for the restaurant and some
Kevin: Guilty Gear inspired NPCs showing up for dinner which is fun.
Kevin: A shame it's not the full characters, but, uh, fun nonetheless.
Kevin: Yeah, I'm, I actually have not played that much guilty gear.
Kevin: Maybe once it is a off the wall, goofy fighting game with insane, both
Kevin: in personality and flavor and the story and lore may is Japanese.
Kevin: And that's a big deal in the guilty gear universe.
Kevin: That means she has powers.
Chelsea: *laughs* Oh my gosh.
Kevin: So, yeah, yeah, that's a, yeah.
Kevin: their nationality depends on the country.
Kevin: It does determine your school kid in the Guilty Gear world.
Kevin: Regardless, like I said earlier, I'm a little disappointed it's not going both ways, that
Kevin: Day of the Diver isn't being added into Guilty Gear Strive.
Kevin: Maybe, I don't know, Arxis can pull off some crazy nonsense, so if anyone could it'd be
Chelsea: You never know. Yeah.
Kevin: them.
Kevin: Regardless, that's a wild and fun one, very happy.
Kevin: There is so much David Diver content!
Chelsea: I know, he's just everywhere. He's just doing anything.
Kevin: And we had the Bancho game. There's definitely room for David Diver month, too.
Chelsea: Dave the Diver Month? Oh my god. Yes! Incredible.
Kevin: We did that a couple years ago! We did David Diver month!
Kevin: Yeah, and it was fun. I loved David Diver. Great game.
Kevin: They just can't stop, won't stop. Good for you, Dave.
Kevin: Okay, that is the news.
Kevin: Short and very sweet. Some delightful gems in there.
Kevin: With that, let us just dive on into our main topic.
Kevin: Chelsea, let's talk about Neopets.
Chelsea: Yes, we have been talking about this for so long.
Kevin: So long. I thought we were just going to greenhouse, but screw it.
Kevin: It's now a main episode.
Kevin: And, you know, I think that's fine.
Kevin: It's not farming, per se, but there's a lot of cottagecore.
Kevin: There's a lot of roots.
Kevin: I think a lot of people who play cottagecore
Kevin: probably touched Neopets at one point in their life.
Chelsea: Oh, they probably started with Neopets.
Kevin: Yup, yup, yup.
Kevin: OK, so you want to go ahead and tell them what Neopets is?
Kevin: Describe it for the viewers who...
Chelsea: Oh my gosh, I don't even know where to start with Neopets.
Chelsea: So, there's no direct plot in Neopets.
Chelsea: So, you can do whatever you want in this game, and no one is going to play the same way.
Chelsea: So, the main objective, I'd say, is have your pets, but you can paint them with paintbrushes,
Chelsea: you can feed them, groom them, read to them, put them in the Battle Dome, zap them with
Chelsea: Elabrae.
Chelsea: There's so much you can do with a
Chelsea: Neopet. There's a map, the land is called Neopia, and there's different lands like
Chelsea: Fairyland, and there's an underwater one, and there's one in space, and there was
Chelsea: one that was destroyed, and there's hidden ones that you have to go through
Chelsea: certain lengths to find, and you can honestly, whatever you think you can do
Chelsea: with them, you can. Because you can collect books, stamps, food, you can gamble, you
Chelsea: can play the stock market, you can do jobs, like there's just so much you can
Kevin: So much gambling.
Chelsea: gamble. If you ever got hooked on the slot machine, you can probably blame
Chelsea: Neopets for that.
Kevin: You legit okay, so for reference right? This is an totally in Bowser or browser in browser game
Chelsea: Yes, this is an in-browser game. They do have an app now.
Kevin: Yeah
Chelsea: It's- I don't know if you've looked up the app.
Kevin: It is I've never touched the app I'm
Chelsea: It's...
Chelsea: It's quite bare-bones. So you have access to your pets.
Kevin: Yeah, I'm not surprised
Kevin: So for reference it came out in what tooth mid 2000s 2003 2004
Chelsea: Yeah, so you-
Chelsea: 97 I think, 98?
Kevin: He's that early good never mind
Kevin: Okay, well, that's when I picked it up. I think that's when it gained a lot of popularity after
Kevin: 2000 mark I would say um
Chelsea: Yeah, but
Chelsea: company wouldn't-- yeah, sorry, first launched in 1999,
Chelsea: but they didn't want to invest a lot into it until after the millennium to make sure that the internet didn't crash.
Kevin: They wanted to make sure we could survive the Y2K virus.
Chelsea: Yes, um, and it can lull you to sleep, the fact that your personal data has probably been breached through Neopets if you ever had a childhood account.
Kevin: [laughs]
Chelsea: Or your childhood pet has been sold on the block market because there is a whole block market for Neopets.
Kevin: Oh.
Kevin: Oh, we'll get to that.
Kevin: Let's put that to the side,
Chelsea: Yes, okay.
Kevin: 'cause there have been issues here and there.
Chelsea: Yeah, we'll say that.
Kevin: So yeah, it's very open-ended, right?
Kevin: It's in-browser game,
Kevin: and it still feels probably the biggest turnoff
Kevin: for a lot of people, or issue it has,
Kevin: because it's so old,
Kevin: much like our favorite webs.
Kevin: site of Pokemon Seraphy. It still has a lot of roots dug deep into those early internet days.
Kevin: There's a lot and they're working on it. They're making a genuine effort to try to update a lot.
Kevin: But you can definitely feel the pains, especially with Flash shutting down a while back. A lot of
Kevin: their games were dependent on that. So they're still trying to work out the kinks on a lot of
Kevin: games. They're not all fully functioning. Right. That's interesting.
Chelsea: Now you just get a tombstone when you click on a flash game.
Chelsea: Yep, they call it the game graveyard.
Kevin: Yeah, that's rough. I can't play my favorite game, Dueling Deck, sadly.
Kevin: Hopefully one day. Yeah, but they've salvaged a lot of other iconic ones, Fairy Bubbles and such.
Kevin: But yeah, so the core concept, right? You have a pet and kind of Tamagotchi style,
Kevin: you're taking care of it. You feed it, you can dress it up. All these things Chelsea mentioned.
Kevin: and you there's an economy you got to earn neo points and you can do that through playing games
Kevin: through the jobs the stock market like she said I think the games are a really
Kevin: big part of the experience because you know that's the most active parts and a
Kevin: lot of iconic games for people who played neopets what are some of your
Chelsea: Oh, my favorite was Myrka Chase, that's the one that's like Snake, basically.
Kevin: Yeah, just snake. Yeah.
Chelsea: Yeah, um, and there was all these cheats you could type in at the start, so you could get zero gravity mode.
Chelsea: There was a whole bunch of different things you could type in, um, to customize the game, it was super fun.
Chelsea: I loved Myrka Chase, I loved Volcano Run, which is basically Floppy Bird.
Kevin: Yeah, it is. It really is. It outdated it. It is.
Chelsea: [laughs]
Chelsea: The OG Floppy Bird.
Chelsea: Uh, that game's broken, though.
Chelsea: I feel like it just doesn't work for me.
Chelsea: Um, I'm trying to think of what other games.
Kevin: I haven't tried it recently, but, um, oh man.
Chelsea: No.
Chelsea: I loved Tug of War.
Chelsea: I remember my parents getting mad at me because I'm just slamming the keyboard.
Chelsea: And they're like, "Can you stop?"
Chelsea: I'm like, "No, I have to win!"
Chelsea: Just decimating the keyboard.
Kevin: Well, that's incredible.
Chelsea: Yeah, what were your favorite games?
Kevin: Um, I just want to comment on Mirka Chase.
Kevin: I like, so there's obviously a lot of snake clones out in the world.
Kevin: Cause it's a very simple game, right?
Kevin: But I like the flavor because you're this neopet called the Mirka and Mirka is
Kevin: like the neg--
Kevin: as they're called, the Neopet eggs.
Kevin: So the thing is, you're grabbing negs,
Kevin: and it just forms this huge chain of eggs behind you.
Kevin: And that's how the snake is growing.
Kevin: I just love the visual of that.
Kevin: But my favorite games--
Kevin: Fairy Bubbles is a classic one, where you're just
Kevin: shooting bubbles to match the colors,
Kevin: and you break them as the screen's
Kevin: kind of scrolling downwards.
Kevin: I-- yeah, it's great music, too.
Kevin: I'm glad they saved that one.
Kevin: One of my favorite games that I'm awful at is Grundo Ball.
Kevin: It's basically keepy-uppy for the Bluey fans.
Kevin: There's a ball or balloon and you kind of keep it up in the air.
Kevin: There's different balls and you just click on it.
Kevin: And so how they bounce around and interact depends on the ball.
Kevin: But the reason it's probably one of my favorite games.
Kevin: There's, like I said, lots of cheats in these games.
Kevin: Grundo Ball has a cheat where on the starting menu there's a
Kevin: spinning Grundo, and if you click on his badge you can actually use the Grundo as a ball
Kevin: itself.
Kevin: You didn't know that?
Chelsea: Oh my gosh.
Kevin: Oh, you didn't know the Grundo is flamable?
Chelsea: No!
Chelsea: No, I didn't!
Kevin: Fire up Grundo Ball and go experience the Grundo.
Chelsea: Okay, I'm gonna do that. I'm gonna do that after.
Kevin: He's probably the best ball because he's the biggest radius, there's a bubble around
Kevin: him basically, it's invisible but you can click anywhere in the bubble.
Chelsea: oh my god we're still learning stuff we're still uncovering things to this day
Kevin: The secrets run deep in the neopets.
Chelsea: [sobbing]
Chelsea: Very appropriate game for children!
Kevin: security bar to prevent a thief from breaking in or entering the bank.
Kevin: Basically it's just a quick reflex game but just so much fun.
Chelsea: oh
Chelsea: that's that reminds me of another game there's one called imperial exam
Chelsea: where you have people line up and you have to see if they spelt the word correctly
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I remember that one
Chelsea: you're basically yeah yeah I was so good at that game I love that game it is i'm like wait
Kevin: Oh, it's so intense go so fast
Chelsea: am I illiterate like or is it just going too fast but I was so good at that game
Kevin: No, I love Neopets because it has this wide range most the games have you know, easy medium hard the hard ones get really
Kevin: And then one of the other games I love
Kevin: Cannot remember. It was like the toy factory game. Do you remember that game there were these?
Chelsea: Is that the... where you match the cards?
Kevin: No, it was
Kevin: so there's this conveyor on top of the screen and there's these plain paint orbs and
Kevin: You have to click on the paint orb and it has to fall into the correct bucket
Kevin: There's like these giant vats
Kevin: There's like red yellow blue orbs
Kevin: and so you have to keep just filling up your orbs because you need the right amounts of paint to
Kevin: Paint the toys that are moving on the bottom assembly line. I can't remember the full name
Kevin: It's like it's some some Toy Factory game
Kevin: It's I love that one again. Just kind of reflexes type game a lot of fun
Chelsea: I would love when you would play the games for a while, and then your eyes would go wonky once the game is done.
Kevin: All right
Chelsea: Everything's slipping back and forth.
Chelsea: One that I cannot play anymore
Kevin: Oh my gosh
Chelsea: is Termack Roll,
Chelsea: where you play as the pet pet, and then you roll across the screen and collect the berries and avoid the obstacles.
Chelsea: That one makes me so sick now. I tried and I just could not do it.
Kevin: I have to try the one, I don't remember that.
Kevin: I remember seeing it, but I don't remember playing it.
Chelsea: Yeah, it was fun.
Kevin: That's interesting, yeah.
Kevin: Oh my God, okay, special mention.
Kevin: There's Whack-A-Cass, you remember Whack-A-Cass?
Chelsea: Oh, Cat Smasher!
Kevin: Yeah, Caspastor, that's what it is, yeah, that one.
Chelsea: Yes, I love that game!
Chelsea: Yeah, I was so bad at it, and then I realized that you need to wait for the wind to get negative.
Chelsea: So, for people that don't know, you have to watch the, the, um, the speed-
Chelsea: Sorry, my cat's yelling at me.
Chelsea: Uh, *laughs*
Chelsea: Um, you have to watch the speed of the wind and angle-
Chelsea: You can use a baguette to whack this, like, bird thing, and then basically it's get it as far as you can.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah. Yeah, that's it. It's.
Chelsea: And that's it! *laughs*
Chelsea: But it was so- It sounds so simple, but it's so hard to time, and like, I just don't even know. I loved that game.
Kevin: It's so intense.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, that's a great one.
Kevin: My favorite thing about Caspash or sometimes
Kevin: because in the game, you might not remember,
Kevin: there's like a tree in the background.
Kevin: Sometimes you could just use the tree as a bat.
Kevin: It was just a random thing that would happen.
Chelsea: Oh yeah, wasn't that like a super random event, you can use the whole stalk of the tree? Yeah.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah.
Kevin: Oh my gosh, that's-
Chelsea: That was fun.
Kevin: Yeah, that was a great one. I love Cas Basher.
Kevin: So that was the games on Neopets, uh, like we talked about there are so much more though.
Kevin: What- let's- I guess let's share some of our personal experiences or personal favorite memories,
Kevin: um, because we've played both as, you know, middle schoolers, high schoolers or whatever,
Kevin: later on in life, just recently picked it up again, uh, so there's a lot of memories here.
Kevin: Tell me some of your favorite experiences.
Chelsea: Yeah, so when I was a kid, that's kind of how I first learned how to customize anything.
Chelsea: There was a girl at my summer camp who was like, "Oh, do you know how to, like, use HTML to customize your Neopets page?"
Chelsea: No, I don't. So she spent, like, the whole summer teaching me how to do it, and it was so fun adding backgrounds to your profile and stuff.
Chelsea: Um, what else? I loved getting my SciBunny, which was...
Chelsea: Yeah, so, okay, so for people who don't know, there's a whole bunch of different species of Neopets, but there are some that are very restricted
Chelsea: and can only be made, um, once a year, and there's some that even then cannot be made on their, um, on their, they call it their pet day.
Chelsea: There's, you have to do, like, secret things to get some of these pets that are really high in demand.
Chelsea: Um, so one of them, one of the original ones, was called SciBunny, which is this really super cute SciBunny, uh, with a really cute, uh,
Chelsea: I don't know what you want to call that, fur on their chest, but I remember getting that and, like, flexing around the school yard, like, "Yeah, I got my SciBunny!"
Kevin: [laughter]
Chelsea: And then there's Chomby, the dinosaur, yeah, yeah, and then I just remember getting ripped off, basically, all the time. All the time.
Kevin: Combee's a good one. Yeah, a little sauropod, rock-e-o-saur sort of guy, yeah. Cute guy.
Kevin: How? What do you mean?
Chelsea: Just people being like, you know, I'm, I'm a little kid, right? And then you go on the Neoboards or you go on Neobale,
Chelsea: "Oh, I'll change you this super rare item for this much, this item," and then you totally get ripped off because you're a little kid.
Kevin: Oh, man.
Chelsea: Um, yeah, but I, coming back, I don't know why I came back.
Chelsea: To be honest, 'cause it was, it's basically held together by spaghetti code now.
Chelsea: Um, but I just wanted to give it another chance, and they have a premium membership now, so have you tried premium?
Kevin: I have not, but I need to with all the perks you've described.
Kevin: [laughs]
Chelsea: It's, I'll let you do your, your favorite things, and then I'll tell you about premium.
Kevin: Yeah, okay, sure.
Kevin: So I didn't interact too much with the community.
Kevin: Like I know the whole Neo boards,
Kevin: Neo forums were a big deal.
Kevin: I didn't interact too many.
Kevin: I mostly kept to myself and my own pets,
Kevin: you know, trying to paint them.
Kevin: Like that was probably my biggest thing.
Kevin: I just wanted to get them into cool colors.
Kevin: I never did.
Kevin: I got like one fairy brush and I didn't even want,
Kevin: I never found the secret lab or all that other stuff.
Kevin: I know I'm such a I played so much and I'm still just a plaid newbie
Chelsea: I keep sending you map pieces, and you keep rejecting them!
Kevin: I know I know I bet I'd
Kevin: I'm a bad neoparent right now. I'm starving all my neo children
Kevin: I am amazed that I was able to log into my account not my original original account
Chelsea: No.
Kevin: But I made a new one back when I was in college and I was able to dust that off. So all my
Kevin: That's still they're not dead
Chelsea: I am so jealous.
Kevin: I have a
Chelsea: I tried to get mine back.
Kevin: Yeah, it's it's it's tough ones that old
Chelsea: It's funny because they tried
Chelsea: They tried to do it for you, but I was what nine and I'm like, okay, they said oh, what was your user name?
Kevin: Yeah
Chelsea: I was like a moon
Chelsea: underscore beams with a Zed
Chelsea: underscore
Chelsea: 76 and they're like, oh, well, we tried that we can't find it. So I said, you know what it's gone
Chelsea: But thank you for trying. I appreciate the hustle. I
Chelsea: Appreciate the initiative to try to get it back
Kevin: Yeah
Chelsea: So was yours hard to get into you had to recover it or?
Kevin: No, I just had to I look through my emails and I was able to find the info I needed I you know
Chelsea: You
Kevin: Basically, I reset a new password, but I was able to get him fairly easily all things considered. Yeah
Chelsea: That's awesome. Yeah, mine was to an old email so I don't even remember what the email was.
Kevin: Yeah, that's the hard part if you don't have the old the same email it's tough
Kevin: So I have a growl a that's a t-rex it's just a t-rex
Kevin: Guy that's all he's got a nice smile
Kevin: He I have a grundo, which is a little alien that I described in grundo ball
Chelsea: He's a cool little guy.
Kevin: He's just a little purple green alien with little antenna
Kevin: He's treated like garbage junk in the neopets lore, but I love my grundo
Chelsea: He really is and because they're like the most populated thing at the pound all you see is grandos in the pound
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, there's
Kevin: There is one event out in the neo world or local
Kevin: Location. It's the abandoned grundo plushie of good fortune or something
Kevin: Just this random grundo plushie hanging on a tree that will sometimes give you money and stuff
Chelsea: excuse you he is called the discarded magical blue grundo plushie of prosperity
Kevin: but
Kevin: That's the one
Chelsea: thank you very much
Kevin: Thank you
Kevin: So I love my grundo my little weird alien, dude. I have and the one I'm really proud of I have a Jetson
Kevin: uh... which is one of the limited pets that you described
Kevin: uh...
Kevin: but I woke up like at six a_m_ on jetson day to make sure I could adopt the jetson
Kevin: and that's how I got my jetson very happy
Chelsea: oh that's right because even yeah for the restricted species they only let
Chelsea: x amount be made per year per day so you're like first in line to get your jet your jetsam
Kevin: yeah
Kevin: yeah basically I made sure uh... and so i'm very happy and jetson is just a shark
Kevin: I like it because there's another new pet called flotsam and it's uh... just a
Kevin: dolphin guy
Kevin: little tough shark guy uh... very very fond of my jetson
Kevin: there's still some other pets I probably want to get there's a hissy uh... wingsnake
Kevin: little new pets I always liked that guy too
Kevin: but uh... but yeah those are my three
Kevin: uh...
Kevin: and so like I said I mostly kept to myself i
Kevin: did a lot of the games uh... I did get into the neopets stock market which is
Kevin: very funny uh how it works it's basically just all
Kevin: rng which one could argue the real stuff market is like too uh they have a wealth of uh fake
Chelsea: Well, yeah.
Kevin: companies and you invest neopoints you know buy shares and you just wait for it to be
Kevin: exceed to be valuable and you sell the shares and you make money that's all there is to
Kevin: it uh for me personally I mean it's just literally a waiting game and checking every day there's
Chelsea: I am terrible at it
Kevin: There's no secret to it, it's all RNG.
Chelsea: did you know that the when the neopets was sold to a new company the head of the company
Chelsea: tanked the stock market in the game yeah yeah he crashed the whole stock market
Kevin: Did he? I didn't know that! That's insane!
Chelsea: before it switched ownership yeah it was super funny
Kevin: That's... that's hilarious!
Kevin: The lore bit I know, when the stock market first released - this was before my time, but I read about it somewhere -
Kevin: some of the companies were actually linked to some of the shops in-game.
Kevin: Like Hubert's Hot Dogs. I don't know if you remember, there was a stand called Hubert's Hot Dogs.
Kevin: Uh, it has a stock and people would basically rig
Kevin: the system where they'd, you know, uh, buy a bunch of stock when it was cheap and then
Kevin: buy a whole bunch of hot dogs to, you know, make the price go through the roof.
Chelsea: Oh my god!
Chelsea: Incredible.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: When you look at insider trading, it was real.
Chelsea: This is a child game, by the way.
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: Oh yeah.
Kevin: And, uh, yeah, there, there are a lot of real worlds because I learned a handful of card
Chelsea: Manipulate the stock market
Chelsea: and become a billionaire.
Chelsea: Preparing us for the real world.
Kevin: games from this game. Real life card games, Solitaire.
Chelsea: Yeah. Did you do cheat? Cheat?
Kevin: and BS. Yeah, cheat, exactly. I do too. There's a Jetson and cheat too. Yeah, it's very cool.
Chelsea: I have the trophy for it. I love that game.
Chelsea: Yeah, that's probably the easiest one to get.
Chelsea: Yeah, and he has like a leather jacket on!
Kevin: So it's cool in my Jetson. I don't go check on my Jetsons that I feel bad. No, I do. Yeah.
Chelsea: [laughs]
Chelsea: We should- Just put them in the Neo Lodge!
Kevin: The neologism, this hotel that they take care of your, you know, pets for free. Yeah, that's
Chelsea: Yeah, so if you don't like the daily characters...
Kevin: That's good.
Chelsea: You can just put them in the hotel. There's different hotels.
Chelsea: Different quality of them in different locations, but ultimately they do the same thing.
Chelsea: So if you don't feel like chucking in every day to feed them...
Chelsea: They always keep them at full...
Chelsea: I guess, yeah, full stomach? I don't know what to call that. Full satiation?
Kevin: - Yeah.
Chelsea: So you don't have to do that every day because...
Kevin: Yeah, satiated.
Chelsea: Yeah, there's different places you can go in the world for free.
Chelsea: There's an omelette that sometimes goes out of...
Chelsea: Yeah, Jelly World, which is a huge conspiracy theory.
Chelsea: And it's like, "Oh, it doesn't exist." But there's this website called Jelly Neo, which is basically...
Chelsea: Your Neopets Bible. So they have a link to every single daily task you can do.
Chelsea: And they have a link for Jelly World. Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Chelsea: And you can get colouring pages on Jelly World. It's super cute.
Kevin: It's yeah jelly world is great the the secret world. They don't acknowledge and you I don't know
Kevin: There's no way to actually access it. You just need the link. There's no way to access it in game. Otherwise, it's great
Chelsea: There's no way to actually feed them.
Chelsea: Yeah, no. But yeah, so some people just don't want to feed their pet or whatever.
Chelsea: So you can put them in the Neo Lodge and it takes care of their basic needs.
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: It is amazing the like economy based aspect of the whole neopets experience because there's so many shops and things you can buy
Kevin: um there's the food there's clothing uh eventually they added like where you could actually
Kevin: dress up your neopets um and uh accessories battle items uh my personal favorite and kind
Kevin: of the business I got into because you can run a shop um is the pet pet business because
Kevin: your neopets can have pets called art pets there is that is correct I have not delved
Chelsea: And your pet pet can have a pet pet pet.
Chelsea: [laughs]
Kevin: that far in because that's the pet pet pet that's real that's some real nonsense that's
Kevin: for the serious people.
Chelsea: It's so funny because a pet pet is pretty cheap, but the pet pet pets are millions of Neopoints.
Kevin: they're so rare, they're so incre- and all the pet pet pets are just like little bugs,
Chelsea: Yeah.
Kevin: they're just like little blips. Yeah. What? Oh my- oh my goodness, you- wow, no wonder
Chelsea: It's just a little guy.
Chelsea: Yeah, I got- I got one. I don't know how I managed to get one, but it was called a slice.
Chelsea: And it looks like a little
Chelsea: Slice and I sold it for like 8 million on the trading post
Kevin: you're rich. I, um, but yeah, so I didn't get into the pet pet pets, but the pet pets,
Kevin: I got into that, because you--
Kevin: There are shops that will sell them, and I can resell them, because there will be some rare spawns or whatever.
Kevin: And so I became kind of a pet-pet wheeler and dealer.
Kevin: I kept a lot for myself, because the pet-pets have fun designs, too.
Kevin: There is this one trio of pet-pets-- I don't remember their names, but they're basically all robots.
Kevin: And if you get them, you can combine them all into the Ultra Pet-Pet 3000-- I forget the name.
Kevin: You haven't seen it? Let me show you.
Chelsea: What? No!
Kevin: Okay, let me show you that. Oh, it's one of my proudest achievements.
Kevin: You know, just get the pet pets. One or two of them are a little rare.
Chelsea: It's so funny because I went on your profile and you still had two pet pets in stock in your store and I bought them.
Kevin: Thank you. Well, I look regardless. So yeah, that's kind of something I do
Kevin: There's a big wide variety because the different worlds and environments kind of influence the different shops and stuff
Kevin: That's one thing. I always liked right you had a desert land the fairy world. You had a spooky haunted woods
Kevin: There was some water worlds and that could influence the type of pet pet you got
Kevin: Or pet pets and foods and items you could buy some there's like a more China Asia inspired land
Kevin: And so you'd have some--
Kevin: Pet Pets inspired by that mythology.
Kevin: So that's why, you know, the whole Pokemon Creature Collector
Kevin: thing was a big part of it.
Kevin: But I was a big fan of Pet Pets.
Chelsea: Yeah, those were cute.
Chelsea: And you can paint them too. You can get their own paintbrushes.
Kevin: Yeah. I
Chelsea: Do you remember, were you around when, um, Morocco was destroyed?
Kevin: think I was, but I didn't pay attention.
Chelsea: It says 2001, so...
Kevin: Oh, no, that was before me then.
Kevin: I think it's very cool.
Kevin: They have a plot and there isn't an overall plot, but there are individual small plots.
Kevin: They'll come out every now and then, there'll be a story you can follow, they'll do events
Kevin: where you can get free items and special items.
Kevin: But a lot of them will actually impact the world and the map, which I think was a very
Kevin: brave thing to do, like the destruction of Morocco.
Kevin: Go ahead, tell me because I wasn't there for that.
Chelsea: that's all I really have to say um there was part there was times where you couldn't access
Chelsea: that part of the map because it was destroyed uh i'm trying to remember it because this is so long
Chelsea: ago I thought at one point the space center had crashed too but apparently i'm that wasn't what
Kevin: Yeah.
Chelsea: happened yes yes yes yes yes
Kevin: Well, you might be thinking of the other big one, which was Fairy World,
Kevin: because Fairy World used to be in the clouds.
Kevin: It was what you'd expect from a place called Fairy World.
Kevin: And, you know, there's rainbows, my little pony looking clouds and rainbow bridges.
Kevin: But then they did a plot line where Fairy World just flat out crashed,
Kevin: fell to the world.
Chelsea: Oh yeah, it says "Fairyland crashed in 2010 when the villain Xandra turned the fairies to stone."
Chelsea: Yeah, so they actually do take some risks with these kind of things and it's
Kevin: I yeah, yeah, I was I actually participated in the fall of favor world plot.
Chelsea: really cool plots you can follow.
Kevin: Um, I have a couple items from that, including a pet bet.
Chelsea: Oh I see your little robot guy! That's so cool!
Kevin: Um, yeah, he's called the old Trump mega bot 2000.
Kevin: That was his name.
Kevin: And he's formed from three different pet bets.
Kevin: And it just literally like stacking them on top of each other.
Kevin: There's pincer on.
Chelsea: Oh, we got to put that in the show notes
Kevin: I think it's for actually, because you need ultra pincer on which is a pincer on and a wheelie.
Kevin: And then you need combo bot, which is formed from two other robo.
Kevin: They're all robo.
Kevin: Puppets Ava bot Neo trick.
Kevin: Those are the names like they're all names.
Kevin: So it's for it's like this megazord Voltron assembly of robot pets.
Kevin: And it's not like is anything special because you don't fight with them or do anything.
Kevin: He's just, you know, for like a lot of other things.
Kevin: Oh, enough.
Chelsea: Just a flex that you have it.
Kevin: Exactly.
Chelsea: Exactly.
Kevin: So that's my big flex.
Kevin: I'm a, I have an ultra mega bot 2000.
Chelsea: It's the only big flex I have.
Chelsea: Is he in your gallery?
Kevin: Maybe I don't fully know.
Chelsea: Because there was a point in time
Chelsea: before galleries were a thing that people
Chelsea: would just put their
Chelsea: I can't remember exactly how to do it
Chelsea: but you would just put it in your shop with like an
Chelsea: unpurchasable price.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I remember that. That's how you showed off.
Chelsea: Yes, just a flex
Chelsea: on people. But now you
Chelsea: have a specific gallery. So for my
Chelsea: Hi Gallery, I'm using um...
Chelsea: I'm collecting potions
Chelsea: But like no one has the same gallery and people do rare books or cards and like no one is playing neopets the same way
Chelsea: Because it is so open-ended some people are super focused on just getting their
Chelsea: pets
Chelsea: Just feeding them gourmet foods because there's some accomplishment if you it's called a gourmet club or something
Chelsea: I can't remember what it's called, but or you can make them read the most books or
Chelsea: Yeah, the bottle dome is a whole other thing. I don't know if you're ever big enough
Kevin: I tried, but it's that's probably one of the weakest parts of the neopets experience in my opinion
Chelsea: I don't want to watch my little guy get knocked out.
Kevin: Yeah, and it's just not a very
Kevin: Intuitive system because training them is not that easy you need to go to certain locations get certain items
Kevin: It's a very slow build up to get any success, and you can get cool items out of it. I think
Kevin: but
Kevin: Especially being, you know, the browser-based game, like, every action is...
Kevin: New page, basically.
Kevin: Oh, there's a Fairy Festival going on right now.
Kevin: It's...
Kevin: Yeah, the Battle Dome, I always wanted it to be a little more, you know, compared to...
Kevin: Obviously, Pokemon is a direct comparison where that's battle-heavy and it's very well done.
Kevin: The battle area, I never could get it to click, really.
Kevin: I tried here and there, I leveled up my guy, but...
Kevin: It was just so much investment to try to get them to where they could succeed.
Chelsea: Yeah, because you could do the Codestones through the training school or there was doubloons for the squash-buckling or swashbuckling academy
Kevin: Yeah.
Kevin: Yep.
Chelsea: And there's a ninja school that I've never used. I don't know, I don't do the ninja school
Kevin: Yeah, exactly.
Kevin: And there were, like, different tiers, and some could train some stats or something, I don't fully remember.
Kevin: There was a lot, it's a deep system.
Chelsea: yeah so I just basically do it just to increase their level but for no reason I like I have one
Kevin: Yeah.
Chelsea: pad that I kind of do the the battle dome for but i'm not really interested exactly number go up
Kevin: Number go up.
Kevin: go up. Yeah, a few.
Kevin: Yeah, won a few matches, but not one of the hardcore battle domers, but I still think about it here and there. I have a Jetson I want him to fight.
Kevin: Yeah, so my ultra mega bot is the pet for my grundo that that feels like a very mean move. I felt bad for grundo. So I gave him the ultra mega bot. So there is one other aspect I want to talk about. And this one's much more.
Kevin: Well, I guess we can talk about the history of neopets a little bit because you know we're talking about the whole
Kevin: site and experience but there's a lot of external to the website of the nonsense that the whole thing has gone through.
Kevin: Sorry, something just popped up on my screen.
Chelsea: - I can't say that.
Kevin: So I will say, so again, I think it got popular right after the turn of the millennium, 2001-2003-ish, a lot of people started hopping on.
Kevin: And it really saw a lot of success in those years, I think.
Kevin: Because we saw it escape containment, as the term is used.
Kevin: We saw have collaborations with McDonald's and
Kevin: the whole line of toys and plushies and games and stuff like that.
Kevin: It was a fairly sizable franchise back in the day.
Kevin: I don't know if you got it up, I don't know.
Kevin: But down here, we had probably the largest.
Kevin: Set of McDonald's toys, because they just did little plushies and they could come in all sorts of colors, right?
Kevin: So you could have a techo, the little lizard guy, but he come like in 10 different colors.
Kevin: Uh, so it was just an insane amount in total of all these plushies you could collect.
Kevin: Uh, I, I had a few myself.
Kevin: I still have a few hanging around, but you could even get some of the cool colors like the story, uh, plushies or the, the shadow plushies.
Kevin: Um, very fearful.
Chelsea: Yes, I remember wanting those ones, the starry ones, really bad.
Kevin: Yeah, this dry one's such a great color aesthetic.
Kevin: Uh, it's blue with yellow stars and there's a lot of pet pet or neopets that get it.
Kevin: Very, very cool.
Kevin: Definitely very aesthetically pleasing.
Chelsea: They also released actual games on the PSP
Kevin: Mm-hmm.
Chelsea: Um, that were horrible
Chelsea: Oh, what was it called? Um...
Chelsea: The Darkest Fairy, I think? Yeah
Kevin: The darkest fairy, that was the big one.
Chelsea: And then there was...
Kevin: I never played it.
Chelsea: There was another one, um...
Chelsea: Pet Pet Adventure's The Wand of Wishing
Chelsea: I had that one on PSP
Chelsea: And now, to this day, like even last year they released
Chelsea: Oh my gosh, what did they call it?
Chelsea: It's like the Arcade Classics collection.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, they just a bunch of them. Yeah, the minigames from the website, which was very fun
Chelsea: So it's a bunch of the minigames that are still broken even on console.
Kevin: Wait, really?
Chelsea: Yeah, it says Mega Minigames Collection on Nintendo Switch, PS5, Steam, Xbox.
Kevin: That's incredible
Chelsea: Includes 26 minigames from the Neopets Games Arcade.
Chelsea: And it's unplayable apparently.
Chelsea: So they kept true to the brand.
Kevin: That's incredible
Kevin: The experience they really captured it faithful remake
Chelsea: [laughs] Yeah. Which sucks.
Chelsea: 'Cause I was considering getting it for Switch.
Kevin: Yeah, that is a shame I thought about it too, um
Kevin: There were also toys and like outside the McDonald's
Kevin: Line, they had a number of toys that I bought
Kevin: they had a couple of action figures because they had several NPCs or characters that were
Kevin: more anthropomorphic
Kevin: versions of the the Neopets right so there's like this gladiator girl I
Kevin: remember I had a toy that I don't just thought it was cool a Neopets action
Kevin: figure there was my sister had a fairy I think I in the earth theory I can't
Chelsea: Ah, jealous.
Kevin: remember her name and then there was yeah it loosened something like that
Chelsea: Oh, illusion or illusion.
Kevin: yeah I'm pretty sure that's what my sister had and it was cool because it
Kevin: It came with like accessories and a little pet pet which was very
Kevin: fun uh yeah that was cool one of my favorite lines was uh the thinkway toys line which one
Kevin: of my favorite toy companies of all time uh here's my toy nerd coming on uh thinkway toys
Kevin: they were big into uh electronics and robotic toys uh maybe not robotics but they were
Kevin: pretty innovative in the early 2000s uh they did a line of pokemon toys actually uh
Chelsea: Oh, are they the ones that you could put in your hand and they would, like, make sound?
Kevin: so they could interact with different things uh they could there was like an ash figure that you
Kevin: could put in the ash figure or a pokedex or a battle stadium and they would all interact and
Kevin: make sounds so I think we might be thinking of the same toys it was very cool uh yeah sounds and
Chelsea: Oh cool!
Kevin: interactivity like that was the big thing and their neopets toys actually very similar so
Kevin: they were basically just hard plastic models of the neopets but they would move around
Kevin: and basically walk and talk and if you put two neopets
Kevin: near each other they would kind of interact with each other which was very cool to see
Kevin: uh you know they were just making random neopet sounds not like actual language but uh you could
Kevin: kind of it felt like they were interacting kind of like in pokopio when two pokemon talk to each
Kevin: other um just two npcs interacting um you know they would emote and move and move their arms
Chelsea: Okay.
Kevin: or walk around or whatever uh very very cool and we had a few of those actually my sister and i
Kevin: Because Melanie was big in Neopets as well.
Kevin: So we had a few of those and that was very cool to see.
Kevin: Just you know that very early Poochie like robot electronic toys wave.
Kevin: A very very fun time yeah.
Chelsea: Yeah, did they have them at, was it Target?
Kevin: Always rust whatever.
Kevin: I don't know what retailers but yeah where I don't fully remember but wherever.
Kevin: I'll try to find a picture.
Kevin: Let me see if I can get you a picture of the Neopet Thinkway toys.
Kevin: But yeah that was a big thing.
Kevin: So yeah, the early.
Kevin: 2000s, very, very long time for Neopets, but it definitely they even had a TCG.
Kevin: I never played it, but I know they had a TCG I had.
Chelsea: Yeah, they still have it in the game.
Kevin: It's yeah, they do, so it's interesting because they I think you could get the McDonald's
Kevin: toys would give you some some like individual cards or whatnot, so I never played the deck,
Kevin: but I had a few cards lying around, and what's interesting...
Kevin: they had a new TCG as well.
Kevin: Like, right now, it's active.
Kevin: They're making new decks and card packs for it.
Kevin: Yeah, and I'll get to it, but...
Kevin: Before that, because...
Kevin: The reason we're talking about Neopets at all,
Kevin: there's been this big push, which I'll get to,
Kevin: but before that, we need to talk about the sell
Kevin: of the Neopets brand to Nickelodeon.
Kevin: Yeah, because...
Kevin: It was doing great, but it fell off.
Kevin: It was kind of a fad sort of situation.
Kevin: Like, you know, they all can't make it and yeah, Neopets.
Chelsea: They were cannibalized.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, they just couldn't keep the momentum and eventually they decided to sell the brand to Nickelodeon.
Kevin: Which was making a big push for online content. That's when the Monkey Quest stuff if anyone knows that brand.
Kevin: That's a brand for Calvin that he knows, but yeah, they were doing a lot of online stuff.
Kevin: And so they acquired Neopets. Now on the one hand it sucks because now you have big Corpo involved, right?
Kevin: But on the other hand, that's a big vehicle and a big brand to push Neopets.
Kevin: Unfortunately, Nickelodeon did not do that. I think it's fair to say they did basically nothing with the brand other than just trying to
Kevin: leech off what was there.
Chelsea: No, we got exposed to immersive advertising. So thanks, Neopets.
Kevin: We did. You're right. I forgot. How could I forget?
Chelsea: The original immersive advertising.
Kevin: I forgot. You could go to the movie theater to watch an ad and get a thousand Neopoints every day or whatever.
Kevin: whatever that was.
Kevin: That's right, that's their big country.
Kevin: Should definitely when a lot of the advertising in the website started in general like right now. I'll be frankly. It's it's awful
Kevin: It's horrendous if you don't you know, we'll still talk about the premium, but the ads on the website is insane
Kevin: The you're just a barrage. It's just ad vomit all over the the borders of the website
Kevin: It really is and that's and that's I think
Chelsea: No, it's unplayable.
Kevin: Nickelodeon's biggest contribution
Kevin: Yeah, they tried a few
Chelsea: I would say so, yep.
Kevin: things. There was a game called Key Quest for a while, which was basically this board game that
Kevin: you could play with multiple people. That was kind of fun, and you could get great prizes from it. I
Kevin: played it a little bit, but it didn't last terribly long. And yeah, Neopets kind of just lingered on
Kevin: in a kind of zombie state under Nickelodeon. Now, it was relatively recently sold off the brand.
Kevin: They sold it off to, I don't remember who, but a private group basically.
Kevin: And I don't remember all the full details of this, but basically at this point, they're free.
Kevin: They are free from the Nickelodeon overlords.
Kevin: They are trying to make a comeback.
Kevin: From what I remember reading, some of the people who bought the brand were genuine fans of the the Neopets site from, you know,
Kevin: back in the day. So they had a genuine effort to
Kevin: work on the brand and the website and modernize it. And it's a work in progress. Let's say that. They're pushing it.
Chelsea: There are like half of the web pages are still the old version of Neopets.
Kevin: Mm hmm.
Chelsea: I don't know if that only happens with Premium, but you'll be redirected to some things that are from the original banners and stuff.
Kevin: Yeah, no, no, it's not premium. I see it too. Yeah, it's a real
Kevin: mishmash of old and new in different parts of the website. It's really funny to see.
Kevin: You get the crisp, clean artwork, and then you get some, you know, pre-2000 scribbles, basically.
Kevin: It's very, very funny.
Chelsea: Do we want to get into the NFTs?
Kevin: Oh, that happened, didn't it? Go, go ahead, tell the...
Chelsea: No, it did not last very long. Basically, they wanted to get into the NFT markets, bless you.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, but that's... I didn't even see them, but I can imagine.
Chelsea: And they were hideous.
Chelsea: They were very, very ugly and it was stolen assets from other artists, like fan artists, not even from the official web.
Kevin: Well, of course, that's what NFT is.
Chelsea: Yeah, not even from the official website.
Chelsea: So the biggest website, like I mentioned before, Jellyneo, had this huge campaign of "Stop NFTs, don't do it."
Chelsea: Eventually, they wanted to make it all into the metaverse and have it be this whole immersive thing.
Chelsea: It all got cancelled and they said, "Okay, we hear you, we're sorry."
Chelsea: This was a few years ago now, but now they're really trying to salvage the fanbase they have left.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah, and I think they're making a genuine effort they're introducing a lot into the website
Kevin: They did a new plot that's lasted like a year. So they did an event in New York and an actual IRL event
Chelsea: It looks so fun!
Kevin: Yeah, it's it's it's cool
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: So overall like
Kevin: It's neopets still in rough shape Chelsea. Tell me about the premium because I I need to do
Kevin: I still want to try neopets. I think it's worth a month from what you've told me. Tell me how glorious the
Chelsea: Yeah, I was very conflicted, but I realized, you know, I've been playing this game for however many years, I can give them 12 bucks a month.
Chelsea: So, price monthly is $7.95 USD, or $70 USD annually.
Chelsea: So for me, that's $11 Canadian, $103 annually.
Chelsea: There are no ads!
Chelsea: No ads, it is like a different game.
Chelsea: Um...
Kevin: It's that sounds like the problem
Chelsea: Yeah, so I personally think they should have a tier-
Chelsea: It's like you pay $2 a month for no ads, and then you don't get any of the additional premium features.
Chelsea: But they don't have tiers like that.
Chelsea: So you have no ads, you got a free species change that is only accessed once every 365 days.
Chelsea: So you can take one of your existing pets, or you can make a new pet, and you can change that into any species.
Chelsea: Including the restricted ones. I think there's one exception, and that one is based on how long you've been a member of Neopets.
Chelsea: So you can do the restricted one. So that's how I got my Psybunny this time.
Chelsea: There's a premium toolbar, so with easy access to the Shop Wizard. So for people who don't know, the Shop Wizard is
Chelsea: this little furry guy that you can type in an item, and he'll give you people that are selling the item.
Chelsea: But with the
Chelsea: regular Shop Wizard, it doesn't show you the cheapest one by default.
Chelsea: It'll just show you ones that are available in a random part of the bazaar.
Chelsea: But if you use the Super Shop Wizard, it shows you the lowest by default.
Chelsea: So you could be saving tons of Neopoints by using the Super Shop Wizard.
Chelsea: Let's see. So that makes up- yeah, he has a jump jump. It makes a huge difference.
Kevin: Yeah, he's a jub-jub. Yeah, that's a Zed.
Chelsea: There are premium only Neoboards, which I'm not crazy about. I don't really care about the Neoboards, to be honest.
Kevin: I'm scared to know what they're like in 2026.
Chelsea: They're very censored.
Chelsea: Like very to the point
Kevin: Oh. Really, wow.
Chelsea: Where you can't even speak properly
Chelsea: Like you can't even you can't say cucumber. You can't say grape
Chelsea: Because all of these things inherently have these words in them
Kevin: What? Oh, yes, that.
Chelsea: So people just go around and there's it has its own slang in that world people get around it
Chelsea: Yeah, oh
Kevin: saying because it was the wild west back in the day, you know, the early internet days.
Chelsea: Yeah, I know they
Chelsea: There was a time a few years ago
Chelsea: I think where someone hacked into it and everyone was swearing.
Chelsea: And it was the craziest thing I've ever seen.
Chelsea: There's some YouTube videos of how the Neoboards looked during that time and it was hilarious.
Chelsea: So what else is there? There's additional random events.
Chelsea: So, for people that don't know, you can just be randomly doing your thing and then a notification will pop up at the top of your page that says "Something has happened!"
Chelsea: And usually it's something good, sometimes you get robbed.
Chelsea: Or your pet gets sick. But with the Premium, I find that I've been getting more map pieces given to me.
Chelsea: Because there are secret maps in the game for the Forgotten Shore and the Lab and it's a whole different- yeah, so you can get those that way.
Chelsea: Sorry, I'm just going through all of them here.
Chelsea: There's the Premium Neo deck, which I don't care about. I never cared about the trading cards in the game.
Chelsea: Some of them are expensive though, like millions of Neo points.
Kevin: Yeah, yeah.
Chelsea: There's the Wheel of Starlight, which is- throughout the- it is really cool.
Kevin: It sounds so cool.
Chelsea: So with the other parts of the map, there is the...
Chelsea: And that's basically just, you spin a wheel, kind of like Wheel of Fortune, you can get something...
Kevin: A lot of gambling
Chelsea: Yeah, a lot of gambling!
Chelsea: There's the Wheel of Monotony, which I think is several hours the wheel spins.
Chelsea: There's the Wheel of Knowledge, which is useless.
Chelsea: There's the Wheel of Extravagance, which is 100,000 Neopoints to spin, and you usually don't get anything crazy.
Chelsea: But for the Wheel of Starlight, you can get retired items this way.
Chelsea: And you can get, yeah, so you can get the retired books, you can get retired stuff.
Kevin: Oh my goodness, that's insane.
Chelsea: animals, I got a drake egg that way. Yeah, so for other people that may have not played as much,
Chelsea: a drake is a restricted species. It looks like a little drake, and it's adorable, but you have to
Chelsea: get it from an egg. And it's difficult to get one. But I was super lucky because in my first week of
Chelsea: premium, I got a marbled drake egg. So not only was it a regular drake, it had a rare color pattern.
Chelsea: So that made my whole month that made it worth it. Usually it's pretty good. I don't think I've
Chelsea: ever gotten anything bad from the Whale of Starlight. You can do Space Fairy vending machine tokens,
Chelsea: which I don't really care about the... again, gambling, I don't care about the vending machines.
Chelsea: You have to get these special tokens that you put in, and you can either get really good or
Chelsea: absolute garbage or nothing. And then there are premium scratch cards you get once a week
Chelsea: from the Space Fairy as well. And that one is a guaranteed win. And then...
Chelsea: I've had decent luck with that.
Chelsea: For people that care about the game submission score, you can submit-- without premium you
Chelsea: can submit your score three times for neopoints, but for premium you can do four times.
Chelsea: So if you're first starting out, that's a good way to work up your neopoints in your
Chelsea: account.
Chelsea: And just everything just runs so much better.
Chelsea: So if you plan to spend any amount of time, even like ten minutes a day, I would say it's
Kevin: without 800 ads.
Chelsea: the premium membership.
Kevin: It sure sounds like it. That's that's a lot of value. So
Kevin: Like, you know what overall this sounds like a better way of monetizing than nfts or all the nonsense
Kevin: they're doing
Kevin: that sounds reasonable if you're
Kevin: Serious about neopets and one try a month, you know, at least a month trial of eight bucks is not bad
Chelsea: Yeah, I try for a month
Chelsea: Because there is another currency. There is another currency in Neopets called neocash
Kevin: Yeah, I'll give a shot
Kevin: Yeah
Chelsea: Some items can only be yeah, some items can only be used with neocash which is real currency
Kevin: The premium
Chelsea: I don't like care about those a lot of that is related to like pet armor and stuff that I'm just not really worried about
Kevin: Yeah
Chelsea: So that's never been worth it for me. But no premium overall. I don't have a lot of subscriptions for games. So I don't mind
Chelsea: Paying it, but yeah, if for someone who even wants to spend ten to
Chelsea: fifteen minutes a day doing anything, I highly recommend the premium because it makes it
Chelsea: unfair to, yeah, honestly, try it for one month and tell me how different it is.
Kevin: me. I will I open up my page right now and I see 1, 2, 3, 4,
Kevin: 5 ads on the screen. Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I get it. Yeah, yeah, I
Chelsea: Yeah, and they follow you down your screen as you're scrolling, they follow you, or they'll be on top of things that you're trying to do.
Chelsea: Or you'll wait for the ads to load before you can do anything, so it's crazy.
Chelsea: They have to make their money somewhere, but you are bombarded with ads.
Kevin: like they're trying to make money and I want them to succeed.
Kevin: I don't know if it's the there's a better route, but they're
Kevin: trying it's better than the NFT days or whatever Nick was doing.
Chelsea: Yeah, the MNFTs, and, *sigh* just crazy.
Kevin: Oh, good times. Oh, Neopets. I still love you. I'll still check in. I'll still play, especially
Chelsea: Do you want me to talk about the black market?
Kevin: Yeah, yes, tell me about yes, I forgot about that tells about the black
Chelsea: Huge, huge thing on Neopets.
Chelsea: Huge thing.
Chelsea: So back, I think it was early 2000s,
Chelsea: they were called unconverted pets.
Chelsea: So before the website was updated,
Chelsea: there was a different art style for older Neopets
Chelsea: called unconverted pets.
Chelsea: And then pets made after a certain date
Chelsea: had a different art style, the more modern art style,
Chelsea: but a lot of people preferred the.
Chelsea: old art style, so people would actually pay real life money to other accounts to have
Chelsea: them be traded or put them in the pound and go through a chain of people to get it back
Chelsea: to this person.
Chelsea: So if you ever had an old account, it's probably been pillaged and all of your old pets have
Chelsea: been sold for real money.
Chelsea: There was one hacker, there was one hacker who I think he was responsible for 49% or
Chelsea: ridiculously high number of password breaches.
Kevin: That's insane!
Chelsea: Like billions upon billions upon billions of Neopoints.
Chelsea: Crazy.
Chelsea: And then there's always the plots, like the annual, I guess it's kind of like the Olympics
Chelsea: in Neopets, it's called the Altador Cup, with different teams.
Chelsea: And there was this huge conspiracy that it was just done by bots and hackers because
Chelsea: the scores, the top scores was like so-and-so team one, so-and-so team two, with the same
Chelsea: username, just different number I think.
Chelsea: end. So it was totally rigged. In July 22, it was announced that 69 million accounts had been
Chelsea: compromised. So crazy that it's yeah, so when I pay for my membership, I use PayPal. They are not
Kevin: Yeah, no that sounds like a good idea
Chelsea: getting my card. They are not getting my card information.
Kevin: That sounds like a very good idea, I don't think I've ever given them money directly, so that's why I don't think I was
Kevin: Affected by the data breaches even though I probably was caught up in it
Chelsea: Yeah, so I had a few childhood accounts, and I guarantee they are gone, because I had some of the older pets.
Chelsea: And, oh, people take it so seriously.
Chelsea: There was one team member for Neopets that had an unconverted pet, but it was made after the conversion date,
Chelsea: so people were just losing their mind, calling out the staff member.
Chelsea: So they changed it back, and then they changed it to keeping him unconverted,
Chelsea: but they put his date of creation as the first day Neopets was ever created.
Chelsea: I personally don't care if the staff have their own custom pets, but there is so much that people take way too seriously.
Kevin: That shenanigans, wow.
Chelsea: And yeah, there's times where pets have been hijacked from other people's homes.
Chelsea: and put in the pound, and basically people will make a trading chain to get up to a rarer pet.
Chelsea: And then if one person in the chain reports it, they basically do the whole chain in reverse.
Chelsea: So people that were involved in a scheme may not have even known that they were in one until they get their pet back.
Chelsea: And it's just, there is so much that goes on.
Chelsea: It is crazy.
Kevin: Wild that's a lot of shenanigans. Oh
Chelsea: A lot.
Kevin: Man hats off to the Neopets like the team in the mods because they've had to put up a lot with a lot
Chelsea: Yeah.
Kevin: fun fact Chrissy
Kevin: Tegan Tegan, I'm not sure how you pronounce her the
Chelsea: Yeah.
Kevin: She used to be a moderator
Chelsea: Yeah, 'cause John Legend was, like, the new face of Neopets for a while.
Chelsea: And I'm like, what are we doing? This is where all the money's going to?
Kevin: Yes. Oh, that's. Yeah, same. Yeah, I'm still I'm still going to be on the ride along for
Chelsea: Celebrity endorsements.
Chelsea: Anyway, despite all of this, I am- this game is very dear to my heart and it makes me happy.
Kevin: whatever they bring our way. I'm like I said, I do think even with all the nonsense we've
Kevin: talked about, I think the game is in the best spot it's been since 2000s probably.
Kevin: Before Nick, it feels hopeful, optimistic. Will it deliver? I can't say. But keeping
Kevin: my fingers crossed. OK, is there anything else you wanted to add?
Chelsea: I will very, very briefly mention this, so Adam Powell was the original creator of Neopets
Chelsea: and he went in the official Neopets discord and people basically went after him because
Chelsea: he was really touting the NFT thing and a new game called Dragons or *clears throat*
Chelsea: excuse me, something like that, and there's photos of him flipping off the camera proving
Chelsea: that it's him.
Chelsea: saying that if you're not getting with NFTs then you don't understand how the world works
Chelsea: and then people were calling him out and like trolling him and one of his there's a whole
Chelsea: song made because one of the lines that he says before he got kicked out of the discord
Chelsea: was I hope you live forever in poverty and the official discord so people have made like
Kevin: Oh my goodness!
Chelsea: t-shirts saying it and songs it's so funny the discourse that has come yeah so um I think
Kevin: Oh, that's incredible.
Chelsea: he's no longer doing any of that but there were times where he was going into people's
Chelsea: discords and development pages basically saying oh I'm rich I I don't need any of this like
Chelsea: y'all just hate on neopets but anyway it was so crazy just to kind of it was really sad
Chelsea: so I hope he's in a better place now but he was going after anybody who would say anything
Chelsea: about NFTs so I mean I guess he made his money and then he had enough time to be looking
Kevin: Wow, wow, that's so sad.
Chelsea: for for things like that yeah
Kevin: Oh, man, because, well, you know, what a vision he had if--
Chelsea: I know. But we're in a better place now, I think, with the team that's there. With their independence.
Kevin: - Yeah, fingers crossed.
Kevin: I haven't heard them talk about AIs,
Kevin: so we're safe right now.
Chelsea: Yes, there are also two spin-off games. Sorry, I'll just mention these quickly
Kevin: [laughs]
Kevin: - Okay.
Chelsea: There's two mobile games what is called Tales of Dracardia and one is Fairy Fragments
Chelsea: So I haven't played Tales of Dracardia very much
Chelsea: It looks like it's like a building game like you develop the land kind of thing
Chelsea: and then Fairy Fragments is like a match three type of game and
Chelsea: If you link them both to your Neopets account you get rewards in your Neopets account like neo points and rare items and stuff
Chelsea: So there is kind of the incentive, but I find Fairy Fragments is actually quite fun
Kevin: Huh, oh, I'm, yeah, I do enjoy Good Mansion.
Chelsea: I thought it was gonna be like Fairy Bubbles, but it's not
Chelsea: It is enjoyable
Chelsea: Yeah, it's actually quite fun
Chelsea: Yeah, so they're in the 21st century now with their companion ops
Kevin: kind of hats that have a foot in the 21st century.
Chelsea: Yes
Chelsea: Right, but no it's a huge expansive world and again. There's no pressure to play a certain way
Chelsea: I don't know anyone who plays it the same way.
Chelsea: There's so many different things you can explore or prioritize.
Chelsea: Yes, there's stamps. Yep, there's the stamps, the avatars that you can use on the neoboards,
Chelsea: the books. There's just so much. No one has the same experience.
Kevin: But I may check it out. We'll see yeah
Chelsea: Yeah, yeah, just another way for them to get your data
Kevin: That yeah, and look actual cottagecore find
Chelsea: There you go exactly
Kevin: Okay, okay any other thoughts or comments or should we call it a day there
Kevin: Okay, that's all I think I've got to say as well, okay
Kevin: Anything else you want to plug or shout out Chelsea
Chelsea: We did it!
Chelsea: I'm shouting out the fact that we finished this episode
Chelsea: because it has been weeks in the making.
Kevin: It's still
Kevin: Yeah, it's and it to the last minute filled with foibles. Um, oh goodness. I'm sorry
Kevin: Yeah, we're about to make you go through
Kevin: Okay, but that said I don't have much else to say
Kevin: So other than thank you, Al. Thank you listeners. Thank you Chelsea for joining us
Kevin: Check out the
Kevin: Podcasts on tumblr and blue sky at THS plot
Kevin: Go to harvest season club to see that everything directly all our show notes links all that good stuff
Kevin: Drop some feedback. Tell us your favorite neopet or
Kevin: pet pet or something
Kevin: Tell us your dream
Chelsea: Has your account been pillaged?
Kevin: As you let us know if you are in a class-action lawsuit, I don't know if there is one but
Chelsea: Yeah, would not surprise me. You may be titled to financial compensation.
Kevin: Yeah
Kevin: Exactly don't reach us out to us about it expecting it, but let us know anyways, cuz that'd be dope
Kevin: You can also go to patreon.com
Kevin: THS pod to see all the good stuff we have including the slack
Kevin: Where you can get some a little behind the scenes some threads you can everyone hangs out we talk
Kevin: There's
Kevin: Many
Kevin: Dark secrets in that slack the the cat between the hosts the cat between me Cody and Al about the draft every week
Kevin: We're just in dismal disarray over all our draft
Kevin: Or you can also get access to the greenhouse
Kevin: Yes, here's our weekly promise of we're gonna make a bunch of greenhouses that we will deliver maybe one day, but not here yet
Kevin: We'll get that
Kevin: That's it's on the list. All right, and until next time dearest listener, thank you for joining us again, but until next time
Chelsea: Have a good Harv-
Kevin: Have a good harvest
Theme Tune: The Harvest Season is created by Al McKinley, with support from our patrons including our
Theme Tune: pro farmers Kevin, Stuart and Elisa. Our art is done by Micah the Brave and our music is
Theme Tune: done by Nick Burgess. Feel free to visit our website harvestseason.club for show notes
Theme Tune: and links to things we discussed in this episode.
Chelsea: And we're back.
Kevin: I'll see have you been recording locally
Chelsea: On my voice recorder for myself.
Kevin: I'll take that. I forgot to hit record on the last
Chelsea: No you didn't.
Chelsea: I only have my side on the voice recorder.
Kevin: I took I have my side. I have local recording. That's okay. We can work with that
Chelsea: Okay.
Chelsea: Sorry, Al.
Kevin: Oh good
Chelsea: [laughs]
Chelsea: [clap]
Chelsea: [squeak]
Kevin: All right, we have the last portion going let's screw the time we'll just go okay
Chelsea: Al, you can fire us.
Chelsea: [sniffles]
Chelsea: [laughs]
Chelsea: It's the Neopets curse.